Guide to the Charles Frederick Park Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles Frederick Park papers
1950-1987
SC0135
Park, Charles Frederick, 1903-
20.75 Linear feet
Collection largely consists of correspondence with professional colleagues and correspondence which covers Park's activities in national and international geological organizations (especially the Society of Economic Geologists and the International Association of the Genesis of Ore Deposits), mineral explorations, work as a mining consultant, and the School of Earth Sciences at Stanford. Other materials include papers, addresses, lectures, research proposals, newsletters, minutes, financial records, reports, articles, and clippings.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Charles F. Park, 1975.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of geology (1946-1969; emeritus, 1969-); and Dean of the School of Earth Sciences (1950-1965).
Description of the Collection
Collection largely consists of correspondence with professional colleagues and correspondence which covers Park's activities in national and international geological organizations (especially the Society of Economic Geologists and the International Association of the Genesis of Ore Deposits), mineral explorations, work as a mining consultant, and the School of Earth Sciences at Stanford. Other materials include papers, addresses, lectures, research proposals, newsletters, minutes, financial records, reports, articles, and clippings.
Access Terms
International Association of the Genesis of Ore Deposits.; Park, Charles Frederick, 1903-; Society of Economic Geologists (U.S.).; Stanford University. Department of Geology. Faculty.; Stanford University. School of Earth Sciences--Faculty.; Geology, Economic.; Geology--Study and teaching (Higher)--California.; Mining geology.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - A - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adair, George L. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adams, R.M. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adent, William A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Agnew, Allen (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Agocs, William B. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alaska Geological Society (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alben, Ruth (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - AAPG (The American Assn. of Petroleum Geologists) - Ind. -Acad. Rel. Com. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Amax Exploration, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Geographical Society (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Geological Institute (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - AAUP (American Assn. of University Professors) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - AIME (American Institute of Mining, Metallurgical and Petroleum Engineers) (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Contains Park paper delivered at AIME meeting in Duluth, Minn. 1/12/70 - "Affluence".
    - AIME Comm: "Ore Deposits of the Western States" (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - American Institute of Professional Geologists (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - American Mining Congress (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Contains 8x18 glossy photo of group, including Park, 1962.
    - American Petroleum Institute (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Contains statement of Park before the Subcommittee on Antitrust and Monopoly, U.S. Senate Hearings, May 28, 1969.
    - Amstutz, G.C. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Andhra University - lndia (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Anglo-Amer. Corp. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Angwin Bindery (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Arents, S.S. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Armstrong, Frank (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ary, T.S. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Aubert, Lloyd L. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - B - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bahia Guimaraes, Paulo (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Bailey, Edgar H. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bailly, Paul (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Baker, A. Jr. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Baker, George (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Banghart, M.D. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Barbat, William F. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Beatty, William (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Blaustein, Morton K. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Bourret, Weston (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Boyd, J. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Bradley, W.H. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Brant, Arthur (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Brazilian Geological Society (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Brown, John S. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bryant, Donald G. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Buder, T.A. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Butler, Robert D. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Butler, W.P. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Byerly, Perry (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - C - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cady, Wallace M. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Callaghan, Eugene (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cameron, E.N. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Campbell, Charles D. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Campbell, Ian (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - CAPES (College Association for Public Events and Services) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Carpenter, R.H. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Chace, F.M. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Childs, Orlo E. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Chile (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Coombs, Howard A. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Commission des concentrations minerales (France) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Cornell University (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Cox, Dennis P. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Crandall, Kenneth H. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - CSIRO (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - D - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Dando, Eion (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - DeGoes, Louis L. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Dickson, Frank (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Dorr, John Van N. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Dutton, Carl E. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - E - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Economic Geologists Foundation, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Economic Geologists Publishing Co. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Eimon, Paul I. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Eisner, Thomas M. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - X1 Boushi, Ismail (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Elliott, J.E. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Encyclopedia Americana (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Evans, David L. (Taffy) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Everhart, Donald L. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - F - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Feiss, Julian W. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Flawn, Peter T. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Foose, R.M. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Forman, John M. Albuquerque (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Fortune (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Frasche, Dean F. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Fraser, Donald M. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Freaman, W.H. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Freaman, Cooper & Co. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Freeze, Arthur C. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Frost, J.E. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Fulton, Robert (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - G -Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Gallo, S.G. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gamble, D.L. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Gauld, Charles A. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Gemmill, Paul (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Geology Dept. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - GSA (Geological Society of America) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - GSA - Council, 1960, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - GSA - Nominations (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - GSA - Penrose Award (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - GSA - P & A Committee (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Gianella, Y.P. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Grant, Robert Y. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Grogan, Robt. M. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Grose, L.T. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Guild, Philip W. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Guimaraes, Djalma (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Gustafson, John K. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Gutierrez, Carlos Garcia (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Gutierrez, Luis Garcia (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - H - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hamilton, Doug (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Hamlin, George H. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Haranczyk, Czeslaw (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Harrington, J.J. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Hart, L.H. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Hedberg, Holllis D. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Helmke, R.F. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Hoots, H.W. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Howell, Fred H. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Hubbert, M.K. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Humphrey, F.L. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Hunt, C.B. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Hunt, L.W. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - L - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Indian Science Congress, 1964 Dec - 1965 Jan (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Infa-Red Microscope (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - IFSEG (International Federation of Societies of Economic Geology) (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - International Geological Congress - XX (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - International Geological Congress - XXI (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - International Geological Congress - XXII - XXIV (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - IGU (International Union of Geological Sciences) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - International Oil and Gas Ed. Center (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Irving, Earl M. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - J - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Jahns, Richard (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - James, H.L. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Jenkins, Olaf P. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Jones, R.H.B. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Jones, Verner (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Journal of Geological Education (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - K - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Kaiser (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Kalliokoski, J. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Kauffmann, V. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Kennecott Copper (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Kesler (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Kettlewell, W.A. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Kiersch, George Alfred (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Koenig, Bob (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Krauskopf, K.B. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Kruger, Frederick C. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Kutina, Jan (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - L - Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Laco Deposit (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Lacy, W.M. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Lambly, C.A.R. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Latin American Studies (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Lectures (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Leigh, Roy E. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Leighton, M.M. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Lindauer, Herman (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Loofhourow, R.L. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Lounsbury, Richard W. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Lowell, J.D. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Lugn, A.L. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Lund, Gage (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - M - Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Mc- Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Mackay School of Mines (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Madero, Enrique (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Manrique, Alberto (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Mapes, Eduardo (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Marcona (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Martinez, Anibal R. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Merriam, C.W. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Mexico (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Charles P. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Minerals Exploration Company (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - MSA ( Mineralogical Society of America) (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Mining & Metallurgical Society of America (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Montana State College Lectures (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Moran, Robert B. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Moran, William R. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Murphy, Thomas D. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - N - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Nagell, Raymond H. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - National Academy of Sciences (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - National Research Council (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Netelbeek, T.A. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - New Mexico Mines (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Newmont (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - New Yorker Magazine (Box 9, Folder 26)
      Correspondence, articles, reviews re. Encounters With the Archdruid by John McPhee, 1971.
    - Nicol, George L. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Nishiwaki, C. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Noble, James A. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Nolan, Thomas B. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - O - Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Oakeshott, G.B. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Occidental Pet. & Min. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Ordonez, G. & J. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Ore Deposits Book (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Osborn, E.F. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - P - Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - P.A. Science Seminar (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Pardee, Franklin G. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Park, G.F., Personal (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Parks, Ernest K. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Payne, Anthony L. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Payne, G.R. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Peninsula Geological Soc. Policy Committee (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Peoples, Joe Webb (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Perry Vincent D. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Pfleider, Eugene P. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Pinger, A.W. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Pioche (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Poland, J.F. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Probert, Alan (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Putzer, Hannfrit (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Q - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - R - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Resources for the Future, Inc. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Reviews (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Roberts, Ralph J. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Rodgers, John (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Rodriguez, Eraso. G. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Ronald Press Co. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Rove, Olaf N. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Russell, Dana (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - S - Correspondence I (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - S - Correspondence II (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Sainsbury, C.L. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Salvatori, Henry (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Saleem, A. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Scheid, Vernon (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Schellinger, A. Kenneth (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Scheechlle, George L. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Science Journal (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Includes Park article "2000 A.D. - People and Resources" (by Park and M.C. Freeman), Jan 1970, with preliminary research material and correspondence.
    - Sharp, Robert P. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Shawe, Daniel R. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Simmons, W.W. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Simons, F.S. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Sims, G.D. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Singewald, Quentin D. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Smith, Ward C. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - SEG (Society of Economic Geologists, Inc.), 1974-75 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - SEG, 1972-74 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - SEG, 1970-72 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - SEG, 1968-70 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - SEG, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - SEG, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - SEG, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - SEG, 1964 Jul - Dec (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - SEG, 1964 Jan - Jun (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - SEG, 1963 Jul - Dec (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - SEG, 1963 Jan - Jun (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - SEG, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - SEG, 1956-61 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - SEG - Lafitte (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - SEG - Magmatic Ore Deposits Symposium, 1966 Nov 12-13 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - SEG, Program Policy Com. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - SME (Society of Mining Engineers) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - SPE (Society of Petroleum Engineers) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Sorem, R.K. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Stanley, G.M. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Staples, L.W. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Steiny, H.J. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Stephenson, Robert C. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Sterling, Dr. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Stose, Anna J. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Swayne, William H. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Szeszich, L. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - T - Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Taylor, Ralph E. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Telfair, Peter (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Thiel, george A. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Travers, William J. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Travis, Maury M. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Trigg, Ernest T. (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - U - Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - U.S. Bureau of Mines (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - U.S. Geological Survey (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - University of Khartoum (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - University of Michigan (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - University of Minnesota (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - University of Sydney (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - University of Texas (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - University of Utah (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Utah International (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - V - Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Visiting Committee (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Voice of America I (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence re. Earth Resources forum of lectures broadcast over the Voice of America in 1971, for which Park was planner and co-ordinator.
    - Voice of America II (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence as described in Box 16, Folder 11. Also includes copies of the lectures including Park's "Resources for the Future".
    - W - Correspondence (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Waentig, Herbert (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Wallace, S.E. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Walstrom, John E. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Ward, Hector J. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Warren Lectures (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Watanabe, Manjiro (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Waterman, Glen (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Wells, Francis G. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - West, W.F. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Whitten, E.H.T. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Williams, Ken L. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Wilson, L.K. (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Wilson, Roy A. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - World Population Book (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Wright, Lauren A. (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - XYZ - Correspondence (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Yugoslavia - Symposium (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE (DECEASED)
    - Arnold, Ralph (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Bateman, Alan M. (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Brooke, J. Kenneth (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Carson, C.M. (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Cranson, Lorin A. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Davidson, Charles F. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - DeGolyer, E. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Dugan, J.F. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - DuShane, Graham (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Fowler, George M. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Fries, Jr., Carl (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Garfias, V.R. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Gault, Dr. H.R. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Gordon, Anthony N. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Horen, Arthur (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Jerome, S.F. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Johnston, Jr., W.D. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Hoover, Herbert (Box 18, Folder 14)
      Includes TLS acknowledgments of birthday greetings from Earth Sciences Dept.; copy of two addresses delivered by Hoover in Belgium on July 4-5, 1958.
    - King, Vernon L. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Levorsen, A.I. (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Longwell, Chester R. (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Longyear, Robert D. (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - MacDiarmid, Roy A. (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Mackin, J. Hoover (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Mahrholz, W.W. (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Marshall, Stewart M. (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Matheson, A.F. (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Mattei, A.C. (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Morris, A.P. (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Owen, Ed. W. (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Pemberton, J.R. (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Roberts, Milnor (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Rockfellow, J.P. (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Rogers, A.F. (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Schenck, Hubert (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Schneiderhohn, H. (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Shenon, P.J. (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Taylor, A.V. (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - NATIONAL MATERIALS POLICY FORUM, Jun 13-16, 1972
    - General material (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Working papers (Box 19, Folder 2)
      Includes Park paper "Minerals adnd United States Policy".
    - Energy Shortage - articles & clippings, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - IAGOD (INTERNATIONAL ASSOCIATION ON THE GENESIS OF ORE DEPOSITS) - GENERAL MATERIAL
    - 1961-63 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Includes Park paper "Zoning in Ore Deposits - the Pulsation Theory and the Role of Structure in Zoning", delivered at a symposium in Prague, Czechoslovakia in Sep 1963.
    - 1964 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Includes material on the genesis and organization of IAGOD.
    - 1965 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Includes further material on the organization and statutes of IAGOD.
    - 1966 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Includes revised statutes.
    - 1967 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence re. symposium in Scotland sep 1967.
    - 1968 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence re. plans for meeting in Czechoslovakia in Aug 1968.
    - 1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      General correspondence.
    - 1970-74 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Material re. IMA-IAGOD meetings in Japan Aug - Sep 1970. This folder also includes carbon copy of letter by Dr. Jan Kutina of Czechoslovakia to the United Nations proposing nomination of an International Committee on the creation of a University of the United Nations and the establishment of a temporary "United Nations Institute of Geological Sciences", dated Jan 31, 1970.
    - Membership, 1967-70 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Further material on membership is also scattered throughout the folders in Boxes 19-21.
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-1989-262
  - General Correspondence
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Geophysical Union (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Institute of Mining Engineers (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Andhra University (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reviews (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Archives (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Assays (misc.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Associates: School of Earth Science (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - B (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Paul A. Bailly (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bill Beatty (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bethlehem Steel (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - California Institute of International Studies (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Clube de Mineralogia (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Eric Cheney (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Committee on Tectonics of Ore Deposits (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - D (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - E (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Earth Resources Course (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Ismail M. El Boushi (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Economic Publishing Company (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "Encuentro" (Mexican T.V.) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - F (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Freeman, Cooper, and Company (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Freeman, Cooper, and Company (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - W.H. Freeman and Co. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - G (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Geological Society of America (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Golden Cycle Corporation (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - J.K. Gustafson (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Luis Garc_a Guti_rrez (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - H (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - H (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Marc Haas (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Earl Herkenhoff (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Earl Herkenhoff (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Victor F. Hollister (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - I (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - IAGOD (International Assoc. on the Generation of Ore Deposits) (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - J (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Virgil Kauffman (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Fedrick C. Kruger (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Jan Kutina (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - _______ (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - _______ (Bound Report) (Box 1)
    - Jan Kutina (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - L (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - M (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - M (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Mc (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mexico (misc.) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Mineral Economics (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mineral Information Institute (M.I.I.) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - _______ (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - N (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - New Mexico Tech. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - New Yorker (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - George Nicol (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Thomas B. Nolan (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - O (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - P (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Q (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - R (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - R (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Rocky Mountain Mineral Law Foundation (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - S (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Ender Sahin (Box 2, Folder 33)